Vikram Voleti

PhD candidate at Mila; former Research Intern at Google, Wunity, Meta; 4+ years of work experience

woletiv.github.io

□ vikram.voleti@gmail.com

7 Google Scholar

in LinkedIn

EXPERTISE

Deep learning for image, video, 3D: expert at machine learning research and development; experienced in leading multiple projects collaborating with international partners in industry and academia.

Projects include: • Score-based denoising diffusion models for video [1], deriving non-isotropic covariance [2]

- Image generation using normalizing flows [4][9]; video generation using Neural ODEs [13], GANs [15][16]
- 3D human pose estimation and inverse kinematics [3], 3D object generation using NeRFs, diffusion
- Contributed to projects on 4D generation, simulation [10], fairness/uncertainty [5], federated learning [6]

EDUCATION

Mila, University of Montreal, Canada

Sep 2018 - present (Aug 2023)

Ph.D. in Computer Science — Supervisor: Prof. Christopher Pal

Tindian Institute of Technology (IIT), Kharagpur, India

2009 - 2014

Dual Degree (B.Tech. (Honours) + M.Tech.) in Electrical Engineering with Master's specialization in Instrumentation and Signal Processing

Research Internships DURING PHD Meta (formerly Facebook), Menlo Park, USA

Aug-Dec 2022

Team: AI for Metaverse (AI4RL); Supervisors: Dr. Yashar Mehdad, Dr. Barlas Oguz

- Led the technology development for generating 3D objects, videos from text; diffusion models, NeRF
- Applied expertise at neural graphics for 3D rendering; implemented hands-on in PyTorch • International AI team; technology transitioned into a Meta end product, and adopted by other Meta teams
- Unity Technologies, Montreal, Canada (MITACS Research Intern) Oct 2021 - Aug 2022

Team: Deep Pose, Unity Labs; Supervisor: Dr. Boris Oreshkin

- Built AI-assisted animation workflow for user-editable 3D characters; trained novel 3D human pose prior
- Published at SIGGRAPH Asia [3], incorporated technology into a Unity product
- Google, Mountain View, USA

Sep-Dec 2019

Team: Google AI Perception; Supervisors: Dr. Bryan Seybold, Dr. Sourish Chaudhuri

- Investigated the scope of deep semi-supervised learning for active speaker detection in video
- Hands-on implementation in TensorFlow; collaborated with TPU team for coding Neural ODE in Jax/Flax

Work

IIIT Hyderabad, India — Research Fellow; Supervisor: Prof. C. V. Jawahar

May 2017 - Aug 2018

- EXPERIENCE
- Synthesized educational videos in regional Indian languages by generating lips from audio
- Developed automated pipeline to create large-scale audio-video dataset
- Full paper published at ICASSP 2019 [15], short paper published at CVPR 2018 Workshop [16]

GreyOrange Robotics, Gurgaon, India — Image Processing Engineer

- Developed computer vision solutions for embedded robotics in real time for warehouse automation
- Solely responsible for code development and testing of video processing module, camera drivers, server

Airbus, Bengaluru, India — Associate Engineer

Jul 2014 - Feb 2016

Avionics software development following standard avionics coding guidelines (DO-178B)

OTHER

Blue Lion Labs, Canada — AI Advisor

Oct 2020 - present

Professional

• Provide technical guidance and mentorship on the design and development of AI/ML systems

EXPERIENCE

• Mentor co-op students and interns, published research papers from work led by them [6][8]

NextAI, Canada — AI Scientist-in-Residence

Apr-Sep 2019, Mar-Sep 2020

Provided scientific and technical support to start-ups selected in yearly co-hort of NextAI accelerator

Playment, Bengaluru, India — Computer Vision Consultant

Jan-Jun 2018

• Provided technical guidance on semantic segmentation models for autonomous driving

TalentSprint, Hyderabad, India — Mentor, Foundations of AI & ML (inaugural program) Jan-May 2018 • Designed and delivered tutorials on machine learning, and provided mentorship to industry professionals

Awards

Outstanding Reviewer at CVPR 2021	May 2021
Microsoft Diversity Award for Doctoral Research, \$6,000	Dec 2020
MITACS Accelerate Research Internship, \$30,000	Oct 2020
University of Montreal entrance scholarship, \$37,000	Sep 2018
IIIT Hyderabad merit scholarship for summer school, \$1,000	Jul 2017

VIKRAM VOLETI Page 1 of 3

SERVICE	Organizer — ICCV 2021 - Differentiable 3D Vision and Graphics workshop OWCV 2021 (Canadian Computer Vision workshop), Canada GRAPHQUON 2020 (Canadian Computer Graphics workshop), Canada	Feb-Oct 2021 Feb-Apr 2021 oda Oct-Dec 2020
	Reviewer — Journal on Computer Vision and Image Understanding, CVPR 2022, ACML 2021, NeurIPS 2021, ICCV 2021, CVPR 2021 (<i>Outstanding Rev</i> ICLR 2020, NeurIPS 2020, ICML 2020, NeurIPS 2019, CCAI @ ICLR 2020, CCAI @ NeurIPS 2019, LLD @ ICLR 2019	iiewer),
TEACHING EXPERIENCE	D () I D (A: 1 A 1	
	 University of Montreal, Montreal, Canada — Teaching Assistant Fundamentals of Machine Learning (IFT 6390) by Prof. Ioannis Mitliagkas 	$Sep ext{-}Dec~2020$
	Summer Symposium on AI Research, India — Guest Speaker	Jul~2020
	 University of Montreal, Montreal, Canada — Teaching Assistant Fundamentals of Machine Learning (IFT 6390) by Prof. Ioannis Mitliagkas 	Sep 2019
	IVADO/Mila Deep Learning School, Montreal, Canada — Teaching Assistant	Sep 2019
	AI for Social Good Summer Lab, Montreal, Canada — Lecturer	May 2019
	TalentSprint, Hyderabad, India — Mentor, Foundations of AI & ML (inaugural progration of Designed and presented tutorials on machine learning, and mentored industry progration.)	,
Past Internships	 KU Leuven, Belgium — Supervisor: Prof. Ingrid Verbauwhede, ESAT Designed and implemented carry-free arithmetic operations in Verilog; simulated of 	Summer 2013 circuits in Xilinx
	 IIT Kharagpur, India — Supervisor: Prof. Aurobinda Routray, Electrical Engineering Made a gesture recognition program in MATLAB using Hidden Markov Models 	Summer 2012
	 Imperial College, UK — Supervisor: Prof. Peter Cheung, Electrical & Electronics Circuits and Systems Research Group; measured intra-die power variation in sub- 	Summer 2011 nm FPGAs
SKILLS	C/C++, CUDA, HTML/CSS, Javascript, Jax, Keras, LATEX, MATLAB, OpenCV, OS Shell, SLURM, Tensorflow, Ubuntu, Verilog, Windows Deep learning, computer vision, machine learning, research and development, gener score-based diffusion models, normalizing flows, Neural ODEs, GANs, Transformers, lar generation, video prediction, 3D pose estimation, 3D rendering, text-to-image, text-to-3.	ative modeling, NeRF, ge-scale training, image
Talks	"Diffusion models for solving video tasks" — INRIA, France [slides]	Feb 2023
THEIRS	• "MCVD: Masked Conditional Video Diffusion" — NeurIPS 2022, New Orleans, USA	
	 "SMPL-IK: Learned Morphology-Aware Inverse Kinematics for AI Driven Artistic V — SIGGRAPH Asia, Diagu, South Korea [slides, video] 	
	• "Normalizing flows" — Learning Representations (course), University of Montreal, C	Canada Nov 2022
	• "Score-based Denoising Diffusion Models - a tutorial" — Mila, Canada [slides, video	Sep 2022
	• "Solving Video Tasks using Denoising Diffusion Models" — Samsung Toronto, Cana	da [slides] Aug 2022
	• "MCVD: Masked Conditional Video Diffusion" — Mila, Canada	May 2022
	• "Denoising Diffusion GANs" — Mila, Canada [slides]	Feb 2022
	• "Training GANs by Solving ODEs" — Mila, Canada [slides]	Apr 2021
	• "Score-based Generative Models with SDEs" — Mila, Canada [slides]	Feb 2021
	• "Continuous Normalizing Flows" — Mila, Canada [slides]	Sep 2020
	• "GANs: the story so far" — Summer Symposium on AI Research, India [slides, vide	_
	• "A brief tutorial on Neural ODEs" — Mila, Canada [slides, video]	Jul 2020
	• "Mathematics of Neural ODEs" — University of Guelph, Canada [slides]	Apr 2020
	"Simple Video Generation using Neural ODEs" — IIIT Hyderabad, India [slides] Tytopial on "CANO" — All for Social Cood Symmetry Leb Montreel	Jan~2020
	• Tutorial on "GANs" — AI for Social Good Summer Lab, Montreal	11 0010
	• "RigGAN" — Mila University of Montreal Canada [alidea]	May 2019
	 "BigGAN" — Mila, University of Montreal, Canada [slides] "Image de-fencing using RGB-D data" — MPI Informatics, Saarbriicken, Germany [Oct 2018
	 "BigGAN" — Mila, University of Montreal, Canada [slides] "Image de-fencing using RGB-D data" — MPI Informatics, Saarbrücken, Germany ["Intuition behind LSTMs" — IIIT Hyderabad, India [slides] 	Oct 2018

VIKRAM VOLETI Page 2 of 3

Feb 2017

THESIS
PROJECTS

• "Mathematics of back-propagation" — GreyOrange Robotics, India [slides] Supervisor: Prof. Rajiv Sahay, Electrical Engineering, IIT Kharagpur, India

Master's thesis — "De-fencing of Images using RGB-D Data"

2013 - 2014

- Elimination of fence-like occlusions, and inpainting of images using RGB-D data
- Nominated for Best Project Award among three departments, research work published at ICAPR 2015

Bachelor's thesis — "Identification of Bilabial Lip Closures in Audio and Video"

2012 - 2013

• Measurement of synchronization between audio and video using bilabial cues in both modes

RESEARCH PAPERS

[1] NeurIPS 2022 - "MCVD: Masked Conditional Video Diffusion for Prediction, Generation, and Interpolation", V. Voleti, A. Jolicoeur-Martineau, C. Pal [arXiv]



- [2] NeurIPS 2022 Workshop "Score-based Denoising Diffusion with Non-Isotropic Gaussian Noise Models", V. Voleti, C. Pal, A. Oberman [arXiv]
- [3] SIGGRAPH Asia 2022 "SMPL-IK: Learned Morphology-Aware Inverse Kinematics for AI-Driven Artistic Workflows", V. Voleti, B. N. Oreshkin, F. Bocquelet, F. G. Harvey, L. Ménard, C. Pal [arXiv]
- [4] Submitted to a journal "Multi-Resolution Continuous Normalizing Flows", V. Voleti, C. Finlay, A. Oberman, C. Pal [arXiv]
- [5] ICLR 2022 "FairCal: Fairness Calibration for Face Verification", T. Salvador, S. Cairns, V. Voleti, N. Marshall, A. Oberman [arXiv]
- [6] CVIS 2022 (Oral) "Plankton-FL: Exploration of Federated Learning for Privacy-Preserving Training of Deep Neural Networks for Phytoplankton Classification", D. Zhang, V. Voleti, A. Wong, J. Deglint
- [7] Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence (journal) "Generative Models of Brain Dynamics", M. Ramezanian-Panahi, G. Abrevaya, JC. Gagnon-Audet, V. Voleti, I. Rish, G. Dumas [arXiv]
- [8] FSS at AAAI 2022 "Towards Generating Large Synthetic Phytoplankton Datasets for Efficient Monitoring of Harmful Algal Blooms", N. Bamra, V. Voleti, A. Wong, J. Deglint [arXiv]
- [9] ICML 2021 Workshop "Improving Continuous Normalizing Flows using a Multi-Resolution Framework",
 V. Voleti, C. Finlay, A. Oberman, C. Pal
- [10] ICLR 2021 "gradSim: Differentiable simulation for system identification and visuomotor control", K. M. Jatavallabhula, M. Macklin, F. Golemo, V. Voleti, L. Petrini, M. Weiss, B. Considine, J. Parent-Lévesque, K. Xie, K. Erleben, L. Paull, F. Shkurti, D. Nowrouzezahrai, S. Fidler [arXiv]
- [11] MLSys 2021 "Accounting for Variance in Machine Learning Benchmarks", X. Bouthillier, P. Delaunay, M. Bronzi, A. Trofimov, B. Nichyporuk, J. Szeto, N. Sepah, E. Raff, K. Madan, V. Voleti, S. E. Kahou, V. Michalski, D. Serdyuk, T. Arbel, C. Pal, G. Varoquaux, P. Vincent [arXiv]
- [12] ICML 2020 "Learning to Combine Top-Down and Bottom-Up Signals in RNNs with Attention over Modules", S. Mittal, A. Lamb, A. Goyal, V. Voleti, M. Shanahan, G. Lajoie, M. Mozer, Y. Bengio [arXiv]
- [13] NeurIPS 2019 Workshop "Simple Video Generation using Neural ODEs", V. Voleti, D. Kanaa, S. E. Kahou, C. Pal [arXiv]
- [14] ICML 2019 Workshop "Comparing Normalization in Conditional Computation Tasks", V. Michalski, V. Voleti, S. E. Kahou, A. Oritz, P. Vincent, C. Pal, D. Precup [arXiv]
- [15] ICASSP 2019 "Cross-Language Speech Dependent Lip-Synchronization", V. Voleti, A. Jha, V. P. Namboodiri, C. V. Jawahar [pdf]
- [16] CVPR 2018 Workshop "Lip-Synchronization for Dubbed Instructional Videos", V. Voleti, A. Jha, V. P. Namboodiri, C. V. Jawahar (FIVER) [pdf]
- [17] ICAPR 2015 "A Multimodal Approach for Image De-fencing and Depth Inpainting", S. Jonna, V. Voleti, R. R. Sahay, and M. S. Kankanhalli [pdf, IEEE]

Vikram Voleti Page 3 of 3